# DIAKODUE OGHENERUKEVWE

#### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

#### Contact

# Career Objective

+2349092005886



lokosman5@gmail.com



Ikosi, Lagos 100244

Self-taught full-stack developer with extensive experience in React, Node.js, and MongoDB. A passion for technology and a strong understanding of software development principles. Experienced in working on both team and individual projects, with a strong desire to continuously learn and grow. Open to working as an intern or for free in order to gain more experience and share knowledge in developing and implementing software solutions. Skilled in object-oriented programming, web development and database technologies. Excellent problem-solving and communication skills and demonstrates a passion for learning and implementing new technologies.

# Experience

## FULL-STACK DEVELOPER AT MONTIONPIC (2022-PRESENT)

Jan 2022 - Present

**MONTIONPIC** 

- Developed and maintained a motion picture online booking web application using React for the frontend and Node.js with Express for the backend
- Collaborated with a team of designers and developers to ensure the project met the client's needs and expectations
- Implemented and maintained the application's database using MongoDB.

#### SELF-CONTAINED TEACHER

Jan 2021 - Jan 2021

SELF EMPLOYED

- Develop Loytech website and work on numerous projects as a self-employed full-stack developer
- Converted website mockups into pixel-perfect responsive websites compatible with all devices.
- Stylized web pages to reflect attractive designs.

#### **TEACHING ASSISTANT**

Jan 2014 - Jan 2014

MINT INNOVATIONS

- Worked with a small group of 3 individuals to teach kids more about robotics application and how to develop android mobile application
- Assisted in the creation and delivery of lesson plans and hands-on activities
- Encouraged and motivated students to explore their creativity and develop their technical skills

### Education

#### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION & COMMUNICATION TECHNOLOGY SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

May 16 | PRESBYTERIAN UNIVERSITY COLLEGE

#### SENIOR SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE

Sep 09 | STANDARD INTERNATIONAL COLLEGE

#### Skills

- Node.js
- Express
- MongoDB
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Java
- Demonstrated ability to think outside the box and find innovative solutions to complex
- Communication
- Team Player
- Problem-Solving

# **Key Skills And Achievements**

Developed creative solutions for real-world problems using technology.

Demonstrated ability to think outside the box and find innovative solutions to complex problems.

Proven track record of delivering high-quality, user-friendly products that meet the needs of clients and users.

# **Projects**

**Expense Tracker Application** 

Developed an expense tracker application that allows users to keep track of their expenses.

Utilized React for the frontend.

Note App

Developed a simple note-taking application.

Utilized React for the frontend.

Portfolio Project

Developed a portfolio website to showcase previous projects and experience.

Utilized React for the frontend, Node and Express for the backend

Hosted the project on GitHub for preview.